{
    "id": "dffb7fa4c23c48b7b8f6fe639e9917d3",
    "title": "Prepositions Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I slept ........................... nine o'clock.",
            "description": "Till and until mean the same. Till is used of time, and to is used of place.",
            "answers": [
                "to",
                "till",
                "until"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "71fb0305190945618992b0d35dc66b4b"
        },
        {
            "question": "I commenced work ......................... 1st May.",
            "description": "Like since, from can be used to denote the starting point however, unlike since, from is used with all the tenses. ",
            "answers": [
                "since",
                "from",
                "for"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "d2ceb5a4a78e4435a5b8ec04eccc1a78"
        },
        {
            "question": "We walked ........................ the end of the street.",
            "description": "Till is not used of place. It indicates time. ",
            "answers": [
                "till",
                "to",
                "for"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "fe69174465814b169ff65e06ee5ac127"
        },
        {
            "question": "The child has been missing ............................ yesterday.",
            "description": "With perfect and perfect continuous tenses, we prefer since and for. Since shows the starting point of something. ",
            "answers": [
                "since",
                "from",
                "for"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "496d78ee5dc14d6cac316f856dae2d89"
        },
        {
            "question": "He traveled seventy miles ......................... two hours.",
            "description": "When 'in' is used before a noun indicating a period of time, it means 'at the end of'. ",
            "answers": [
                "for",
                "in",
                "by"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "916e2b5604064e74bc43c35d29c0bc92"
        },
        {
            "question": "I received this message ....................... 7 o'clock .................. the morning.",
            "description": "We use 'at' before clock times and 'in' before morning and evening.",
            "answers": [
                "in, at",
                "at, at",
                "at, in"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "f69350614a7448518648f557bfc85341"
        },
        {
            "question": "I saw him felling a big tree .................... a hatchet.",
            "description": "With denotes the instrument and by denotes the agent. ",
            "answers": [
                "by",
                "with",
                "off"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "40cd28ed55f64105bef2f503d355f775"
        },
        {
            "question": "An old feud existed ................... the two families.",
            "description": "We use between to speak of two people or things we use among to speak of a group of people or things. ",
            "answers": [
                "between",
                "among",
                "within"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "d1a994e35bb34426b79e76c470667aa2"
        },
        {
            "question": "......................... Peter and John, there were three other boys present.",
            "description": "Beside means by the side of besides means in addition to. ",
            "answers": [
                "Beside",
                "Besides",
                "In addition"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "5839cd4c5bad48b3ac3c6b5bd7a250d4"
        },
        {
            "question": "He was stabbed .................... a lunatic ................ a dagger.",
            "description": "With denotes the instrument and by denotes the agent. ",
            "answers": [
                "by, with",
                "by, by",
                "with, by",
                "with, with"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "a2552612240f458e903f92fb7428839e"
        },
        {
            "question": "She dislikes being looked .........................",
            "description": "Words like look, stare, shout etc., take the preposition at.",
            "answers": [
                "on",
                "at",
                "in"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "d061bd8e4e97457295d69f5bdc1b1f77"
        },
        {
            "question": "Don't throw food ...................... the dog.",
            "description": "Throw at indicates an idea of attack. Throw to is used when there is no idea of attack. ",
            "answers": [
                "at",
                "to",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "a9be6408c77d4f4eb49daee62c3baf28"
        }
    ]
}